(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-31T02:18:22.855872",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
完全生3D Acoustic Live in Summer
[Acoustic Live in Summer - Full 3D Live]
残響散歌 / 作詞：aimerrhythm 作曲：飛内将大
Zankyou Sanka / Lyrics: aimerrhythm, Composition: Masahiro Tobinai
誰が袖に咲く幻花
A phantom flower blooming on someone's sleeve
ただ そこに藍を落とした
Merely dropped indigo there
派手に色を溶かす夜に
Adding flair to a night melting colors
銀朱の月を添えて
as we add a vermilion moon
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if tumbling
つまずくごとに強くなった
I grew stronger every time I stumbled
光も痛みも怒りも全部
Embracing the light, pain, anger, everything,
抱きしめて
holding them tight...
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If you're not chosen, then you can just choose!
声を轟かせて 夜のその向こうへ
Let my voice roar beyond the night
涙で滲んでいた あんなに遠くの景色まで
Soaked with tears, to the scenery so far beyond...
響き渡れ
...let it echo!
何を奏でて 誰に届けたくて
Playing what music? Wanting to reach whom?
不確かなままでいい
Remaining uncertain is fine
どんなに暗い感情も
No matter how dark the emotions,
どんなに長い葛藤も
no matter how long the conflict,
歌と散れ 残響
scatter with the song, reverberation!
だ・だら・だら・だ・だ
Da-da-ra-da-ra-da-da
だ・だら・だら・だ・だ・ら
Da-da-ra-da-ra-da-da-ra
ただ一人舞う千夜
Dancing all alone for a thousand nights
違えない帯を結べば
Tying an unbreakable band
派手な色も負かすように
As if to defeat even the loudest of colors,
深紅の香こそあわれ
the scent of crimson is so sorrowful.
この先どんな辛い時も
No matter how hard the times lying ahead,
口先よりも胸を張って
I'll be full of pride more than mere words,
抱いた夢の灯りを全部
Just following all the lights of dreams...
辿るだけ
...that I embrace.
逃げ出すため
I didn't come all this way...
ここまで来たんじゃないだろ
...just to run away, right?
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If you're not chosen, then you can just choose.
声をからして
Shout yourself hoarse...
燃える花のように
...and like a burning flower...
闇間を照らしたら
...once you light up the darkness.
曖昧すぎる世界を
Turn this far too-vague world...
譜面にして
...into a musical score.
夜を数えて 朝を描くような
Like counting the nights and drawing the mornings,
鮮やかな音を鳴らす
let a brilliant sound play.
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regret,
どんなに高い限界も
no matter how high the limit...
かき消して
...drown it out...
残響
...reverberation!
だららった ったらったった
Da-ra-ra-ta, ta-ra-ta-ta...
だららった ったらったららら
Da-ra-ra-ta, ta-ra-ta-ra-ra-ra...
はーい！ということで、ホロアコースティックライブ
in Summer 始まりましたー！
Hi! And with that, Holo Acoustic Live
in Summer has officially begun!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Woohoo!
始まった、始まった！
It's started, it's started!
はい！ということで、お越しくださってる皆様、
ありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you so much to everyone
who tuned in to join us today!
それでは最初に、自己紹介を
それぞれさせていただきたいと思います！
First, we would love to go ahead
and do our introductions!
まずは、ホロライブ6期生、
秘密結社holoXの頭脳、博衣こよりだよー！
Starting off, I'm Hakui Koyori, the brain
of Secret Society holoX, from Generation 6!
よろしくお願いします！ / イェーイ！よろしくー！
Pleased to meet you! / Yay! Nice to meet you!
はい！そして1曲目から来てもらった、
まずはミオ先輩！
Next up, joining us from the very first song,
we have Mio-senpai!
うちうち！うちだよ！大神ミオだよ！
ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオです！
It's me, me! Mio here! Ookami Mio!
I'm Ookami Mio from Hololive Gamers!
よろしくお願いします！ / イェーイ！
Pleased to meet you! / Yay!
そして！ / あ、私？
あはは、ちゃんと自己紹介しないと！
And next! / Oh, me?
Haha, you have to introduce yourself properly!
森カリオペです。ホロライブEnglishの死神です。
よろしくお願いします！ Let's have fun, everyone!
I'm Mori Calliope, the Grim Reaper of Hololive EN.
Pleased to meet you! Let's have fun, everyone!
イェーイ！ / Everyone!
Yay! / Everyone!
お忙しい中、アコースティックライブに
出演していただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for joining us
on this acoustic live amidst your busy schedule!
はい、そしてですね、今回はなんと、
ピアノも生演奏でお届けさせていただきます！
Yes, and this time, we are bringing you
a live piano performance!
こよりの生誕ライブでも演奏していただきました、
ウイングさんです！
Performing today is Wings-san, who also
played at my birthday celebration live!
わお、素敵！ / 美しい！
ファンサも素敵！
Wow, lovely! / Beautiful!
Even the fan service is great!
嬉しい！ / 嬉しいですね。
So glad! / Truly delightful.
このライブはですね、最初から最後まで、
完全生放送、生演奏でお届けしますので...
This live show is brought to you fully live,
with live instruments, from start to finish...
よしなに、よろしくお願いいたします！
...so please sit back, relax, and enjoy!
なんでこのライブを
やることになったかと言いますと...
Now, as for how this live concert
came to be...
普通のライブって、ダンスレッスン頑張ったり、
ゲストパートは収録でやったり...
Normal lives, like birthday or anniversary shows,
require intense dance practice and pre-recordings...
モニター作ったりとか、とにかく準備が大変なんですよね！
...along with background visuals.
Essentially, the prep work is incredibly tough!
超大変！ / いっぱいやることある！
Super tough! / There's just so much to do!
そう、1つ作るのにも凄く時間がかかるんですけど...
Right, putting even one together takes
a massive amount of time...
アコースティックなら、集まって演奏して
歌ったら、当日でいけるんじゃね？っていう...
...but with an acoustic set, if we just gather,
play, and sing, could we do it all on the day?
チャレンジをしてみました！ / 素敵なチャレンジ！
That's the challenge we took on! / A lovely challenge!
はい、でも歌ってもらうので、
皆さんには大変なんですけれども...
Yes, though singing it all live makes it
quite demanding for the guests...
いや、でも楽しかったよー！ / めっちゃ楽しかった！
No way, it was so much fun! / Super fun!
嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
I'm so glad! Thank you so much!
カリの衣装とお揃いみたいな感じだね！
/ そうそう、いい感じにまとまってるね！
It feels like we match Calli's outfit!
/ Yeah, it ties everything together nicely!
そう、このカラーリングの並びになりました！
Exactly, that's why we lined up
based on this color scheme!
今、ちょっとコメントが
止まっちゃってるかもしれないんですけど...
Right now, the comments on stream
might be frozen...
また動き出すと思うので！あと、
トレンド今3位まで行ってます、ありがとうございます！
...but they should move again! Also, we are
currently trending at #3! Thank you so much!
トレンド3位！ / 早い、早い！
Trending at #3! / That was so fast!
そんな感じでハッシュタグ
「#holoAcousticLive」使ってください！
With that in mind, please share your thoughts using
the hashtag "#holoAcousticLive"!
スクショも、感想も、全部見ますので、
ぜひツイートしてください！
I'll be looking at all your screenshots and
tweets, so please keep them coming!
さて、1曲目は「残響散歌」でしたけど、
ミオ先輩どうでしたか？
Now, our opening song was "Zankyou Sanka".
Mio-senpai, how did you find it?
はい！えーっと、すごい、
こうやって、なんだろうね...
Well! It was really... how do I put it...
一緒に歌うのめっちゃ楽しいよね！
...singing together like this is just so much fun!
楽しい！ / 歌に集中できますからね、アコースティックだと
It is! / You can really focus on the vocals
with an acoustic arrangement.
かっこいい曲をこうやって歌うの、
すごい楽しかったなって
Singing such a cool song in this style
was incredibly enjoyable.
Mio-chiも おちょは大好きだし
I love Mio-chi so much too.
こよも最近ね 歌めっちゃ頑張ってて
Koyo has been practicing singing so much lately
すごい上手くなったからさ
and she's gotten so good!
嬉しい！ちょっと緊張しちゃった 1曲目だけど
I'm so happy! I was a little nervous, even though it was the first song.
ちょっと一緒に歌えてすごいテンション上がりました ありがとうございました！
But singing together really got my energy up! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！ カリ先輩どうですか？
Thank you very much! Calli-senpai, how was it for you?
おお かっこいい曲大好きです！
Oh, I love cool songs!
いやー でも実はこちら この曲あんまり知らなかったから
Yeah! Actually, I didn't know this song very well...
あ、知ってたけど なんか歌ったことなかったから
I knew of it, but I'd never sung it before.
何回も練習して
So I practiced it over and over,
少しずつ上手くなってきてるかもしれないけど 頑張りました
and maybe I've gotten a little better. I did my best!
素晴らしい
Amazing!
素晴らしい！もう元々知ってると勝手に思うぐらい
Wonderful! You were so good I thought you've known it forever.
上手だった！ 完璧でした！ありがとうございます
It was perfect! Thank you so much.
かっこいい曲です
It's a really cool song.
こちらこそ
Likewise!
Nice choice.
コメント生き返ってる？
Are the comments coming back to life?
生き返った、よかった、おかえり！
They're back! Thank you, welcome back!
よかった、見てる見てる
That's great. They're watching, they're watching.
はい、ということでね、構成的にはね...
Right, so regarding the setlist...
今日は夏っぽい曲を揃えて
Today we've gathered summer-like songs,
イン・サマーな感じでやりたいなと思って 選曲してたんですけども
hoping to perform with an "in summer" vibe, and set up the playlist.
結構ね 夏の曲ってエモい曲が多くて
But summer songs actually have a lot of emotional vibes.
しっとりね_
Very mellow ones, right?
でも一発目はやっぱりかっこよくバーンって盛り上げて 始めたいなと思ったので_
But for the first song, I really wanted to start with a bang and get hyped up!
これを選びまして、ちょっとかっこいい2人に挟まれて「だ、大丈夫かな...？」みたいな感じだったんですけど_
So we chose this, though being sandwiched between two cool people, I was like, "A-Am I gonna be okay...?"
なんか一緒に歌えてめちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
But singing together was incredibly fun!
かっこよかった！ よかった！ありがとうございました_
You looked cool! I'm glad! Thank you so much.
ありがとうございます！_
Thank you very much!
はい、ということで、それではそろそろ次の曲に行く..._
Right, with that said, it's about time to call...
メンバーを、お呼びしたいと思います！_
the members for the next song onto the stage!
ビジュー！_
Bijou!
Did you introduce?_
Will you introduce yourself?
えーっと、ポン・ビジュー！ホロライブEnglish Adventの輝く宝石、古石ビジューだよ！_
Um, Pon Bijou! I'm the shining gem of Hololive English Advent, Koseki Bijou!
キラキラ、古石！_,s:
Sparkle sparkle, Koseki!
キラキラ〜！_
Sparkle sparkle~!
Thank you for coming, Bijou!_
ちっちゃい_
She's so tiny!
みんな、みんな癒される。かわいい！_
Everyone is so healed by you. So cute!
ちっちゃい。ありがとう！_
So small! Thank you!
ね、このあとビジュー、singing？どう？_
So, Bijou will be singing after this. How are you feeling?
Can you do it?_
ちょっと緊張。_
A little nervous.
ちょっと緊張？かわいい〜_
A little nervous? So cute~
はい、ではこのあとはですね、2曲続けてお届けさせていただくんですけども、次の曲は..._
Okay, from here on, we'll be bringing you two songs back-to-back, and the next song is...
カリ先輩とビジューの2人で！_
by Calli-senpai and Bijou!
Yeah! Represent, represent!_
Represent?_
エモくない感じなのかな？_
I wonder if it's not a mellow song?
あのね、ちょっとヒップホップなのかな、どうなのかな？_
You know, maybe a bit of hip-hop? How will it be?
Rock!_,s:
Rock!
Oh, yeah?_
さあ、どんな曲なのか？_
Well, what kind of song is it?
Rock and roll._
ロックンロール？ ロックンロールかも知れない_
Rock and roll? It might be rock and roll!
激しいかも？_
Maybe it's intense?
かも知れない！_
It might be!
でも2人のね、声にめちゃくちゃ合う曲を選んでますので、堪能していってください。_
But we've chosen a song that perfectly fits their voices, so please enjoy.
選曲したんだよね、今回はね。_
You selected the songs this time, right?
そうですね、セトリは決めさせていただきました！_
Yes, I had the pleasure of deciding the setlist!
ありがとう！_
Thank you!
なので、堪能していただけると嬉しいなと思います！_,s:
So, I hope you all enjoy it!
では、我々は一緒に、客席に行きましょう。_
Well then, let's head down to the audience seats together.
オッケーです！_
Okay!
ゆっくり休んでください。_
Please get some good rest!
いってらっしゃい、2人とも、頑張ってね！見てるよ！_
Off you go, good luck to you both! We'll be watching!
See you!_
Just you and me now, rock._
Yeah, yeah, yeah, English time, English time._
大丈夫ですか？ 大丈夫ですか？_
Are you okay? Are you okay?
英語話せるかな、まあ、話さなくてもいいよ、楽しもう！_
I wonder if we can speak English. Well, you don't have to, let's just have fun!
Let's sing a song!_
Yeah._
Rock..._
...and roll. Wait, rock and roll._
Rock, roll._
Okay, we are rock and rolling!_
And now, please listen everyone, to "Kaze to Issho ni"!_
歩きつづけて
I continue to walk,
どこまでゆくの？
how far will I go?
風にたずねられて
Asked by the wind,
立ちどまる
I stop in my tracks.
ひとつめの太鼓
The first drumbeat
トクンとなって
went ba-dump,
たったひと...
and a single...
…つの
...one
命始まった
life has begun.
やがて何かを求めて
Soon, searching for something,
小さな手のひらを広げ
spreading open those small hands,
君はすぐに見つけたね
you found it right away, didn't you?
君じゃない誰かを
Someone other than yourself...
誕生日に祝う
The birthday we celebrate...
ローソク増えたけど
...has more candles now,
ただひとつの
but you left...
ふるさと旅立った
...your only hometown behind.
今も何かを求めて
Still searching for something today,
大きな瞳が輝いて
with your big eyes shining bright.
君のポケットの中には
Inside your pocket...
君じゃない誰かとの
...lies something from someone other than you:
いくつかの出会い
A number of encounters,
いくつかの別れ
a number of goodbyes,
幻のような思い出も少し
and even a few dream-like memories.
歩き続けて
As you keep walking...
どこまで行くの
...how far will you go?
風にたずねられて
When asked by the wind,
空を見る
you look up at the sky.
歩き続けて
As we keep walking...
どこまで行こうか
...how far shall we go?
風と一緒にまた
Together with the wind,
歩きだそう
let's start walking again.
大地ふみしめて
Treading firmly on the earth,
どこまでも行こう
let's go as far as we can,
目指したあの夢を
until we grasp that dream...
つかむまで
...we aimed for.
大地ふみしめて
Treading firmly on the earth,
どこまでも行こう
let's go as far as we can,
目指したあの夢を
until we grasp that dream...
つかむまで
...we aimed for.
ラララ ラララ ラララ…
La la la, la la la, la la la...
ラララ…
La la la...
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've forgotten already...
夏の木陰に座ったまま
...how we sat in the summer shade,
氷菓を口に放り込んで
throwing ice cream into our mouths...
風を待っていた
...and waiting for the wind.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've forgotten already...
世の中の全部嘘だらけ
...that everything in this world is full of lies,
本当の価値を二人で探しに行こうと笑ったこと
and how we laughed, saying we'd go search for its true value together.
忘れないように
So that I won't forget,
色褪せないように
so that it won't fade,
形に残るものが全てじゃないように
so that things that remain in shape are not everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
夏が来るって教えて
tell me that summer is coming.
僕は描いてる 眼に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
I am drawing... what was reflected in my eyes is the ghost of summer.
風にスカートが揺れて
A skirt sways in the wind,
思い出なんて忘れて
Forget all of your memories,
浅い呼吸をする
And breathe in shallowly.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wipe away the sweat as summer begins.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've forgotten by now,
夏の木陰に座った頃
back when we sat in the shade of the summer trees.
遠くの丘から顔出した雲があったじゃないか
There was a cloud peeking out from the distant hill, wasn't there?
君はそれを掴もうとして
You tried to catch it,
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
with your hand foolishly slicing through the empty air.
僕は紙に雲一つを書いて
I drew a single cloud on a piece of paper,
笑って握って見せて
smiled, and showed it to you in my fist.
忘れないように
So that we don't forget,
色褪せないように
So that it doesn't fade away,
歴史に残るものが全てじゃないから
Because what is left behind in history isn't everything.
今だけ顔も無くして
Erase our faces just for now,
言葉も全部忘れて
Forget all of our words,
君は笑ってる
You are laughing,
夏を待っている僕ら亡霊だ
we are ghosts waiting for summer.
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart,
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me the scent of summer,
浅い呼吸をする
And breathe in shallowly.
忘れないように
So that we don't forget,
色褪せないように
So that it doesn't fade away,
心に響くものが全てじゃないから
Because what resonates in our hearts isn't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
さよならだって教えて
Teach me even how to say goodbye,
今も見るんだよ
Even now, I still see
夏に咲いてる花に亡霊を
a ghost in the flowers blooming in summer.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Give me time, instead of words,
時間じゃなくて心を
Give me your heart, instead of time,
浅い呼吸をする
And breathe in shallowly.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wipe away the sweat as summer begins.
夏の匂いがする
The scent of summer lingers in the air.
もう忘れてしまったかな
I wonder if you've forgotten by now,
夏の木陰に座ったまま
while still sitting in the shade of the summer trees.
氷菓を口に放り込んで
Throwing ice cream into our mouths,
風を待っていた
and waiting for the wind.
はい、ということで「花に亡霊」でした！
Yes! And so, that was "Hana ni Borei"!
AZKi先輩、ようこそ！
AZKi-senpai, welcome!
お邪魔します！
Thank you for having me!
イェーイ！
Yay!
こんこんこんこんこん、こんAZKi！
Kon-kon-kon-kon-kon, Kon-AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図、
With a mic in my right hand and a map in my left,
あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！ということでAZKiです！
I'll ZeroGuess your heart! I'm AZKi!
ようこそです！
Welcome!
すごい、素敵なライブにご招待いただきありがとうございます。
Wow, thank you so much for inviting me to such a wonderful live stream.
こちらこそご出演いただきありがとうございます。
The pleasure is all mine! Thank you so much for performing with me.
嬉しい。
I'm so happy.
Me too.
この曲はですね、あの、
Well, as for this song...
AZKi先輩にちょっと歌いたい曲アンケートみたいな、すごい前にね
we did a survey a while ago about songs we'd like to sing with you.
アンケートありましたね。
Yes, we did have that survey.
はい、そちらで、おかゆと一緒に歌いたい曲のところに書いてくださっていた楽曲でした。
Yes, and this was one of the songs you wrote down that you wanted to sing with me.
そうです。やっぱり「夏」って聞いて、
Exactly. When I think of "summer",
この曲は外せないなと思いまして。
I felt this song was absolutely indispensable.
そうですね！
I agree!
しかもあの、アコースティックにめちゃくちゃ合う。
And it fits so perfectly with an acoustic arrangement.
みんなでゆったりになってくれてるみたいです
It seems like everyone is relaxing.
あ、よかった、よかった！ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank goodness! Thank you so much!
こよちゃん、なんと！はい、Xトレンド1位！
Koyo-chan, guess what! Yes, trending #1 on X!
えー！嬉しい！
Eh! I'm so happy!
わあ！みんなありがとう！ありがとうございます！
Wow! Thank you everyone! Thank you so much!
もっともっと呟いちゃってください。嬉しい！ありがとう。
Please post more and more. I'm so happy! Thank you.
それではですね、もっと語りたいこともあるんですけども、
Well then, there's more I'd love to talk about, but...
そろそろ次の曲に行きたいと思うのですが、
...it's about time we move on to the next song.
次のメンバーをまず呼び込みたいと思いますよ！
First, let me call out the next members!
ミオ先輩と、ビボ！
Mio-senpai and BiBo!
ミオちゃん！ビボ！いらっしゃい！
Mio-chan! BiBo! Welcome!
元気！元気！元気有り余ってる！
Full of energy! We have too much energy!
すごいな、ちょっとエモくてしっとりみたいな
That's amazing. We should make it emotional and calm.
ね、しっとりしたね。
Yeah, it became really calm.
そうですね、二人で...
That's right, the two of them...
あれ？あれ？そっちからだったから？
Wait, what? Was it from that side?
二人は元気してたのですね。すごい。
You two were very energetic. Amazing.
はい、偉い！
Yes, admirable!
偉い？偉い？
Admirable? Admirable?
エモい！エモい！エモい！偉い！
Emo! Emo! Emo! Admirable!
エモースティック？ん？エモスティック？エモッティク？
Emoplastic? Huh? Emotick?
エモーショナル？エモーショナルね！
Emotional? Emotional, right!
はい、エモーショナルにお届けしております。
Yes, we are presenting this emotionally.
ではですね、ここでちょっとAZKi先輩、お着替えに...
Now then, AZKi-senpai is going to go change...
お着替えしてきます！はい、お願いいたします！
I'll go change! Yes, please!
エモーショナルといえば、ロックンロールかと思っていた
Speaking of emotional, we thought it was rock 'n' roll...
こより先輩とビボの「風と一緒に」もめっちゃ良かったですよ！
...but Koyori-senpai and BiBo's "With the Wind" was also amazing!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
なんかみんな「え？ロックじゃないの？」みたいに戸惑ってるの
Everyone was confused, like, "Wait, isn't it rock?"
ロックじゃないよ、ロックじゃないよ。
It's not rock, it's not rock.
あ！お帰りなさい！早い！早い！
Ah! Welcome back! So fast! Fast!
はい、というわけで、夏はね、エモい曲が多い感じですけど、次からはどうなるのか？
Yes! So, summer has many emotional songs, but what's next?
ここからは、3曲続けてお届けいたします。
From here, we will bring you three songs in a row.
次の曲はですね、こちらのAZKi先輩、ミオ先輩、ビボちゃんの3人に歌っていただきますので、
For the next song, AZKi-senpai, Mio-senpai, and BiBo-chan will sing for you!
こよりはしばらくバイバイです！頑張ってね！いってらっしゃい！
So Koyori will say bye-bye for a bit! Good luck! Have fun!
ここで一発やっぱりロックンロール？
How about a blast of rock 'n' roll here?
え？ロックンロール？台本にないことを！
Eh? Rock 'n' roll? That's not in the script!
戸惑ってる、戸惑ってる。はい、というわけでね、
They're so confused. Yes, indeed...
ここから3曲続くんですけど、じゃあこの3人で歌わせていただきます。
Three songs will continue from here, so the three of us will sing now.
それでは聞いてください。「スパークル」
Please listen to: "Sparkle."
スパークル [original ver.]
作詞・作曲：野田洋次郎
[Song: Sparkle [original ver.]]
[Lyrics/Composition: Yojiro Noda]
まだこの世界は
This world still seems to
僕を飼いならしていたいみたいだ
want to keep on taming me.
望み通りだろう 美しくもがくよ
Just as it wishes, right? I'll beautifully struggle.
互いの砂時計
Let us kiss while watching
眺めながらキスをしようよ
each other's hourglasses.
さよならから
From our farewells,
一番遠い場所で待ち合わせよう
let's meet up at the furthest place.
ついに時はきた
The time has finally come.
昨日までは序章の序章で
Until yesterday was just the prologue of prologues.
飛ばし読みでいいから こっからが僕だよ
You can skim through; my main chapter starts from here.
経験と知識と
With experience, knowledge,
カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
and a somewhat mildewy courage,
未だかつてないスピードで
at a speed higher than ever before,
君の元へダイブを
I'll dive to you.
まどろみの中で 生ぬるいコーラに
In a doze, with a lukewarm cola,
ここでないどこかを夢見たよ
I dreamed of somewhere far away from here.
教室の窓の外に
Outside the classroom window,
電車に揺られ運ばれる朝に
jolted by the train, carried into the morning...
あー
Ah...
運命だとか未来とかって
No matter how far words like "fate" or "future"
言葉がどれだけ手を伸ばそうと届かない
reach out to us, they cannot touch
場所で僕ら恋をする
the place where we will fall in love.
時計の針も二人を
The clock hands proceed,
横目に見ながら進む
taking a side glance at the two of us.
そんな世界を二人で
Through such a world, together,
一生 いや何章でも
for our entire lifetime, no, for any number of chapters,
生き抜いて
let us live...
いこう
...on together.
「はじめまして」なんてさ
Let's banish words like "Nice to meet you"
遥か彼方へと追いやって
far into the distance,
千年周期を
and live a thousand-year cycle
一日で息しよう
in a single day.
辞書にある言葉で
I hated this world
出来上がった世界を憎んだ
made up entirely of dictionary words.
万華鏡の中で
Inside a kaleidoscope,
八月のある朝
on that morning in August,
君は僕の前で
in front of me,
ハニかんでは澄まして見せた
you acted shy but put on a straight face,
この世界の教科書の
with a smile just like
ような笑顔で
the textbook of this world.
嘘みたいな日々を 規格外の意味を
I wished for unbelievable days, for extraordinary meaning,
悲劇だっていいから望んだよ
even if they were a tragedy.
そしたらドアの外に
And then, there you stood outside the door,
君が全部抱えて立っていたよ
holding every single piece of it.
運命だとか未来とかって
No matter how far words like "fate" or "future"
言葉がどれだけ手を
extend their hands,
伸ばそうと届かない
in a place far out of reach,
場所で
there,
僕ら遊ぼうか
shall we play?
愛し方さえも
Even the very way to love
君の匂いがした
carried your scent.
歩き方さえも
Even the very way of walking
その笑い声がした
sounded like your laughter.
いつか消えてなくなる
One day, everything about you
君のすべてを
will fade away,
この眼に焼きつけておくことは保存
so burning it all into my eyes
もう権利なんかじゃない
,s:
is no longer just a right,
義務だと思うんだ
but a duty, I believe.
運命だとか未来とかって保存
No matter how far words like "fate" or "future"
言葉がどれだけ手を
,s:
extend their hands,
伸ばそうと届かない
,s:
in a place far out of reach,
場所で僕ら恋をする
we will fall in love.
時計の針も二人を
Even the hands of the clock
横目に見ながら進む
glance sideways at us as they move forward.
そんな世界を二人で一生
In a world like that, let's live on together for a lifetime—
いや、何章でも
no, for any number of chapters—
生き抜いていこう
let's live on.
ガーネット
[Garnet]
グラウンド駆けてくあなたの背中は
Your back as you run across the schoolyard
空に浮かんだ雲よりも自由で
is freer than the clouds floating in the sky.
ノートに並んだ四角い文字さえ
Even the square characters lined up in my notebook
すべてを照らす光に見えた
looked like a light illuminating everything.
あー...
Ah...
好きという気持ちが分からなくて
I couldn't understand the feeling of love,
二度とは戻らないこの時間が
but this time which will never return,
その意味をあたしに教えてくれた
taught me the meaning of it.
皆さん、お待たせしましたー！
Everyone, thank you for waiting!
ちょっと生ならではという感じで、原因不明の機材トラブルが起きてしまいまして...
We had some unexpected equipment trouble of unknown cause, which is typical of a live stream...
今のところ、あの、原因も分かってないんですけども...
As of right now, we still don't know the cause, but...
わお！わお！
Wow! Wow!
I was singing so good, it broke the stream! Ah, ah...
お待たせしました、復旧したので...
Thank you for waiting, since we're back online...
改めて、ガーネットから始めさせていただこうと思います！
Let's start once again with "Garnet"!
皆さんお待たせしてごめんね。なんかちょっとビリビリってなったみたいで、耳とかも...
Sorry to keep you waiting, everyone. It seems there was a crackle, so your ears...
え、調子合わせながら、このアコースティックライブで耳直していただければと思います、はい。
...well, while getting adjusted, I hope you can soothe your ears with this acoustic live. Yes.
はい。
Yes.
では、ウィングさんも、ありがとうございます。添えていただきありがとうございます。
And thank you, Wing-san. Thank you for accompanying us.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
では、いきますか？
Well then, shall we start?
はい、おっけー？
Yes, ready?
おっけー！
Ready!
ガーネット
[Title: Garnet]
グラウンド駆けてく あなたの背中は
Your back, running across the ground,
空に浮かんだ 雲よりも自由で
Is more free than the clouds floating in the sky.
ノートに並んだ 四角い文字さえ
Even the square characters lined up in my notebook
すべてを照らす 光に見えた
All looked like light illuminating everything.
好きという気持ちが 分からなくて
I didn't understand the feeling of love,
二度とは戻らない この時間が
And this time that will never return...
その意味を あたしに教えてくれた
...taught me its meaning.
あなたと過ごした日々を この胸に焼き付けよう
I will engrave the days spent with you in my heart,
思い出さなくても 大大丈夫なように
So that I will be fine even without remembering them.
いつか他の誰かを 好きになったとしても
Even if I fall in love with someone else someday,
あなたは ずっと
You will always be...
特別で
...special...
大切で
...and precious,
またこの季節が めぐってく
As this season comes around again.
初めて二人で 話した放課後
The first time we talked together after school,
誰も知らない 笑顔探していた
I was searching for a smile that nobody knew.
遠くであなたの はしゃいでる声に
Hearing your playful voice in the distance,
なぜだか胸が 痛くなったの
For some reason, my chest began to ache.
変わってゆく事を 怖がってたの
I was afraid of things changing,
ずっと友達のまま いれる気がした
And felt we could stay friends forever.
終わってくものなど 無いと思うほど
To the point of thinking nothing ever ends...
果てしない時間の中で あなたと出会えた事が
In this endless flow of time, meeting you...
何よりもあたしを 強くしてくれたね
...strengthened me more than anything else.
移りゆく明日に 辿り着いたとしても
Even if we arrive at the shifting tomorrow,
あなたは ずっと
You will always be...
特別で
...special...
大切で
...and precious,
またこの季節が やってくる
As this season comes around again.
いつまでも 忘れないと
That you'll never forget...
あなたが言ってくれた夏
...the summer that you promised me.
時間が流れ 今頃あたしは
Time has passed, and now...
涙が こぼれてきた
...tears have begun to fall.
あなたと過ごした日々を この胸に焼き付けよう
I will engrave the days spent with you in my heart,
思い出さなくても 大丈夫なように
So that I will be fine even without remembering them.
好きになったとしても
Even if I fall in love with someone else,
あなたは ずっと
you will always be...
特別で
...special...
大切で
...and precious to me...
またこの季節が 巡ってく
...as this season comes around again.
打上花火
[Title: Fireworks]
あの日の見渡した渚を
The shore we saw that day...
今も思い出すんだ
...I still remember even now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words we carved into the sand...
君の後ろ姿
...the sight of your back as you turned away.
寄り返す波が足元をよぎり
The returning waves wash over our feet...
何かをさらう
...and carry something away.
夕凪の中
In the evening calm...
日暮れだけが通り過ぎて行く
...only the twilight passes us by.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
With a flash of light, they bloomed, we watched the fireworks.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely, this summer is far from over...
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
...and has dissolved our uncertain hearts, tying them together.
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
あと何回君と同じ花火を見られるかなって
I wonder how many more times I can see the same fireworks with you...
笑う顔に何が出来るだろうか
...what can I do for the sake of your smiling face?
傷つくこと 喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と情動
Hurting, rejoicing... the repeating waves and emotions...
焦燥 最終列車の音
...the impatience, the sound of the last train.
何度でも言葉にして君を呼ぶよ
Putting it into words, I'll call your name over and over.
波間を選び もう一度
Choosing the gaps between waves, once more...
もう一度悲しまずに
...once more, so we won't have to feel sad...
済むように
...ever again.
パッと息を飲めば 消えてしまいそうな光が
A light that seemed like it would disappear if we let out a gasp...
きっとまだ胸に住んでいた
...surely still lived on in our hearts.
手を伸ばせば触れた あったかい未来は
The warm future we could touch if we reached out our hands...
ひそかに二人を見ていた
...was secretly watching the two of us.
パッと花火が
With a flash, the fireworks...
夜に咲いた
...bloomed in the night...
夜に咲いて
静かに消えた
...and silently disappeared.
離さないで
Don't let me go...
離れないで
...don't leave me.
もう少しだけ
Just a little longer...
...just a little longer...
このままで
...let us stay like this.
あの日の見渡した渚を
The shore we saw that day...
今も思い出すんだ
...I still remember even now.
砂の上に刻んだ言葉
The words we carved into the sand...
君の後ろ姿
...the sight of your back as you turned away.
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
With a flash of light, they bloomed, we watched the fireworks.
きっとまだ終わらない夏が
Surely, this summer is far from over...
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
...and has dissolved our uncertain hearts, tying them together.
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever.
...続いてほしかった
...to go on forever.
ららら...
La la la...
はい！ということで
Alright! And with that...
カリオペちゃんと「打上花火」を歌わせていただきました！
Calliope-chan and I performed "Uchiage Hanabi"!
花火綺麗でした
The fireworks were beautiful.
イェーイ！
Yay!
うわぁ、楽しかった！
Wow, that was so fun!
どうでしたか？
How did you like it?
わぁ、とても楽しかったよ！
Oh, it was so much fun!
嬉しい！カリオペちゃんとこうやって
デュエットできる日が来るとは...
I'm so happy! To think the day would come
when I'd get to duet with you...
思わず、もう本当に...
...I never would've imagined. Really...
いえいえ、頑張りました低い声で
No, no, I did my best with my lower register.
かっこよかった！めちゃめちゃかっこよかった！
You were so cool! So, so cool!
ありがとう！コントラストがすごい好きだから
Thank you! I really like contrast,
低い声でやりたいなと思って
so I wanted to sing in a lower register.
そうなんだね。男性パートをね、
I see. You did such an amazing job
頑張って歌ってくださいました
singing the male part.
カリオペちゃん、ありがとう！
Thank you, Calliope-chan!
こちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you as well!
楽しかった
It was fun.
楽しかった！
It was fun!
ということで...
And with that...
ここでね、またメンバーのみんなを呼びたいと思います！
I'd like to call the other members out again!
全員集合！
Everyone, gather up!
Come on!
カモン、カモン！/ イェーイ！
Come on, come on! / Yay!
最高だった！
That was awesome!
楽しかったね！
It was so fun!
ずっと最高です！本当に素敵でした。ありがとうございます！
It's been awesome the whole time!
It was truly wonderful. Thank you very much!
ということでですね、改めまして、本日はアコースティックライブ...
And so, once again, thank you so much...
...出演いただき、そして見ていただき、ありがとうございます！
...to everyone who performed and watched
today's Acoustic Live!
ありがとう！ / Thank you so much! / Thank you guys!
Thank you! / Thank you so much! / Thank you guys!
もう本当に、選曲神だったなって自分で思うぐらいね、
Really, the setlist was so god-tier that...
皆さんの歌声が...（自画自賛、自画自賛）
...even I can't help but brag about
everyone's singing voices... (Self-praise!)
自画自賛するくらい皆さんが本当に素晴らしくて、
But everyone was so wonderful
that it's worth bragging about,
幸せなひと時を過ごさせていただきました。ありがとうございます！
and I've had such a happy time.
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます！素敵な機会を！
Thank you for this wonderful opportunity!
はい、というわけですね、なんと次が...
And so, incredibly, the next one...
最後の曲になってしまいました！
...will be our final song!
えぇー？！ / 今来たばかり！ / 来たばかりだよ！
Ehhh?! / But we just got here! / We just arrived!
ラストはこの全員揃って歌いますので、お楽しみにして頂けると嬉しいんですが、
We'll all sing together for the last song,
so we hope you look forward to it.
ラストに行く前に、せっかくなんでピアノの前で スクリーンショットタイムとかしませんか？
But before that, since we have the chance,
how about a screenshot time in front of the piano?
おぉー！ / いいね！ / 思い出、思い出！
Ohhh! / Great idea! / Memories, memories!
思い出、思い出！皆さんも撮ってください！
Memories, memories!
Everyone, please take screenshots too!
じゃあ、しゃがむね。囲む、囲む。
Alright, I'll crouch down.
Let's surround her!
イェーイ！うれしい！
Yay! So happy!
こよちゃんかっこいい。どうですか？
Koyo-chan looks so cool. How is this?
わーい！イェーイ！
Yay! Woo-hoo!
イェーイ！わぁ、いい写真！
Yay! Wow, what a great picture!
わぁー！イェーイ、イェーイ、イェーイ！
Wow! Yay, yay, yay!
なでなでされてる。皆さん撮れました？
I'm getting headpatted!
Did everyone get the shot?
イェーイ！イェーイ！はい、じゃあ戻りますか？
Yay, yay! Alright, shall we head back?
ぜひぜひツイートしてくださいね。
Please be sure to tweet your screenshots!
思い出になりますね。
This makes a wonderful memory.
アップしてね。行きすぎた、行きすぎた。
Upload them! I went too far, went too far.
ハッシュタグ、ハッシュタグ！
Hashtag, hashtag!
ハッシュタグよろしくお願いします。ありがとうございます！
Please use the hashtag. Thank you very much!
では、最後の曲に行く前に一言ずつ頂こうかなと思いますので、
Now, before we move on to the last song,
I'd like to get a brief comment from everyone.
ビブー、どうだった？
Bijou, how was it?
えっと、めっちゃ楽しかった！
Um, it was super fun!
みんなすごいですね。
Everyone is so amazing.
ビブーもすごかった！ / すごい！
Bijou was amazing too! / So awesome!
えへへ、ありがとう。
Ehehe, thank you.
「Japanese is very good すごい」って コメントいっぱいありました。
There were lots of comments saying
"Japanese is very good, amazing!"
ありがとうございます！日本語、もうちょっと難しいですけど、
Thank you very much!
Japanese is still a bit difficult, but...
でも、頑張ります！
...I'll do my best!
すごかったよ！めっちゃ練習してくれた。 / 本当にすごい！
You were great! You practiced so much.
/ Really amazing!
ありがとう、ビブー！
Thank you, Bijou!
はい。あの、ENのライブ、８月にありまして、 そちらのアーカイブが９月２５日とかだったかな？
Yes. Also, the holoEN live concert was in August,
and I believe its archive is available until around September 25th?
もう少し見れますので、ぜひそちらも見てください！
You can still watch it for a bit longer,
so please check it out!
ありがとう！ / チェック、チェック！
Thank you! / Check it out, check it out!
そして、カリ先輩！ / お、私？
And Calli-senpai! / Oh, me?
あ、もっと歌いたかった！
Ah, I wanted to sing more!
この夜が続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever
あと３倍くらいは歌いたそう。
I feel like singing about three times more.
次回行けそう！ / ね！
We can do that next time! / Yeah!
本当に楽しかったよ。あの、実は私...
It was really fun. Actually, I...
私、昔、あの、スタートから、あの、
Actually, in the past, from the very start,
３Dをゲットした時、
when I got my 3D,
ずっと毎回、あの、生ライブやってた。
I did a live show every single time.
サマー3Dライブ、そうそうそう、やってたから。
Right, we did that Summer 3D Live, so...
まあ、超お久しぶりですね。ずっともっとやりたかったけど、まあ、機会がなくて。
Well, it's been a super long time. I always wanted to do more, but there wasn't an opportunity.
結構収録がね、入るようになったりとかしましたからね。
Yes, we've started doing more recordings lately.
そう、そうね。だから本当にありがとうございます。とても楽しかったです。
Yeah, that's right. So, thank you so much. It was really fun.
カリ先輩が照れてる、照れてる！かわいい！
Cali-senpai is blushing, she's blushing! So cute!
めっちゃかっこよかった！
You were so cool!
カリ先輩は今日ね、Mikoの5周年のライブから駆け付けで...
Cali-senpai rushed over here today right after Miko's 5th anniversary live...
そう！5周年！ハシゴってこと！？
Yeah! 5th anniversary! Double-booking?!
できない、そんなこと！ ハシゴライブ！
I can't believe you did that! Double live show!
あれもチェックしてほしい。
I want everyone to check that out too.
ね！そう、是非ですね、こちらアーカイブもあるので！
Right! Yes, by all means, there's an archive of it as well!
Busy, busy! とても忙しいけど楽しいから、こちらこそありがとうございました。
Busy, busy! It's very busy, but it's fun, so thank you too.
ありがとうございます！そして、ミオ先輩！
Thank you very much! Next up, Mio-senpai!
はい！いや、こうやってね、みんなと一緒に歌うっていうことが楽しかったね。
Yes! Well, singing together with everyone like this was so much fun.
今日、貴重な時間をもらえて本当に嬉しかったです。本当にありがとう！
I was really happy to have this precious time today. Thank you so much!
いや、こちらこそありがとうございます！
No, thank you so much!
本当にミオ先輩はソロライブ終わったばかりで、そっちも大変だったのにも関わらず、本当に出演してくださって！
Mio-senpai literally just finished her solo live, and despite how busy that must have been, she still came out to perform for us!
でも、なんか出たいなって思ったんだけど、なんか、どうなってるか不安だから、ちょっと曲数は少なくしてもらったんだけど...
But, you know, I really wanted to be here. I was a bit anxious about how things would go, so I asked to perform fewer songs...
確かに1曲少ないね！ そうなんですよ。気遣いいただきありがとうございます！
True, one song less! That's right. Thank you so much for being so accommodating!
でも、出れてよかった！ソロライブも本当に最高だったし、アーカイブもありますので、ぜひみなさん見てください！
But I'm so glad you could make it! Your solo live was truly amazing too, and the archive is available, so please check it out, everyone!
はい！ぜひ見てください！
Yes! Please do check it out!
はい！そして、AZKi先輩！
Yes! And next, AZKi-senpai!
はい！いや、本当に今日、いい時間を、最高の時間を過ごさせていただきました。
Yes! Well, I truly had a great time, the best time today.
見てくださった方もありがとうございました！っていうのと、今回こよちゃんが主催してくれて...
Thank you to everyone who watched! Also, Koyo-chan hosted this event...
このライブがありますので、こよちゃん本当にありがとう！
And made this live show possible, so thank you so much, Koyo-chan!
りぃちゃんも、素敵な演奏をありがとうございました。
And Ri-chan, thank you so much for your wonderful piano performance.
ありがとうございました！素晴らしい！
Thank you so much! It was wonderful!
また、インサマーですか？イン、ウィンターあるんですか？
Is there a next one? An 'In Winter' live perhaps?
やりたいな！っていう気持ちを込めて...
With the hope that we can do it...
ね、気持ちを込めてね、4回はできますから、これね。
Yes, with those feelings, we can do it four times, you know.
なので、今日のライブの感想とかを、ぜひぜひ教えていただけたらなと思います！ありがとうござました！
So please let us know your thoughts on today's live! Thank you so much!
お願いします！ ありがとうございます！
Please do! Thank you very much!
そして、AZKi先輩は11月にソロライブが...
And AZKi-senpai has a solo live coming up in November...
はい、ありますので、よかったらぜひ見に来ていただけたら嬉しいです！
Yes, I do! So I'd be really happy if you could come watch it!
めちゃくちゃ楽しみにしております！
We are really looking forward to it!
チケット争奪戦です、今。
Tickets are currently highly sought after right now.
配信チケットもありますので、ぜひみなさんご覧ください！
Streaming tickets are also available, so please check them out!
はい、ということで、今日はこの主催をしてみたのは、みんなの歌を聴きたい、みんなと一緒に歌いたい...
Yes! So, the reason I wanted to host this event today was because I wanted to hear everyone sing, and sing together with everyone...
っていう気持ちがすごくありまして、そしてピアノと一緒に歌いたいっていう気持ちもすごくありまして...
I had those strong feelings, and I also really wanted to sing alongside the piano...
やったんですけど、本当に最高の時間でした！ありがとうございました！
And we did, and it was truly the best time! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
最後の曲はね、ちょっと名残惜しいんですけど、このまま歌わせていただきたいと思います。
It's a bit sad that we are at our last song, but we would love to perform it now.
みなさん、何の曲だと思いますか？
What song do you think it is, everyone?
What song do you think we're going to sing last, chat? Let's see your guesses.
Last song, last song... Guess! What do you think?
ラストソングをゲスできるのかな？
I wonder if they can guess the last song?
できるかな？
Can they?
SSS? アセンション?
SSS? Ascension?
アセンションアーカイブ！ アセンションって思うよね、って話してました。
'Ascension Archive'! We were saying they'd probably think it's Ascension.
確かに！
Indeed!
でも正解はありそうです。
But it seems some people are guessing it right.
ありそう、ありそう！すごい！
Oh, they are! Awesome!
結構割れてますが、結構夏の歌と言えば、というこの曲で締めさせていただきたいと思います。
The guesses are quite split, but we'd like to close with a song that is the quintessential summer song.
それでは聴いてください。「secret base ～君がくれたもの～」
So please listen to... 'secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~'
secret base ～君がくれたもの～
[secret base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~]
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢
With you, the end of summer, dreams of the future
大きな希望 忘れない
I won't forget our big hopes
10年後の8月
Ten years from now, in August...
また出会えるのを信じて
...believing we'll meet again
最高の思い出を
Bringing back the best memories
出会いはふとした瞬間
Our meeting was sudden...
帰り道の交差点で
...at the intersection on our way home
声をかけてくれたね 「一緒に帰ろう」
You spoke to me, saying "Let's go home together"
僕は照れくさそうに
Embarrassed, I...
顔を隠しながら
while hiding my face...
本当はとってもとっても嬉しかったよ
The truth is, I was so, so happy.
あぁ 花火が夜空 きれいに咲いて ちょっとセツナク
Ah, fireworks bloom beautifully in the night sky, making me feel a bit sad.
あぁ 風が時間とともに 流れる
Ah, the wind flows together with time.
嬉しくって 楽しくって 冒険も いろいろしたね
It was so happy and so fun, we went on many adventures, didn't we?
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future, and big hopes—I won't forget them.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを 信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August, ten years from now.
君が最後まで心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that you were crying out "thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile—it's so painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を...
The greatest memories...
あぁ 夏休みも あと少しで 終わっちゃうから
Ah, because summer vacation will be over in just a little while.
あぁ 太陽と月 仲良くして
Ah, may the sun and moon get along well.
悲しくって 寂しくって 喧嘩も いろいろしたね
It was so sad and so lonely, we had many fights, didn't we?
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君が最後まで心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ\
I knew that you were crying out "thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね\
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile—it's so painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を...
The greatest memories...
突然の
Suddenly...
転校で
...transferred to another school,
どうしようもなく
there was nothing we could do.
手紙書くよ 電話もするよ 忘れないでね ぼくのことを
I'll write letters, and I'll call you too. Please don't forget about me,
いつまでも 二人の 基地の中
forever, inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して 夕日を見てから 星を眺め
Always talking through the end of summer with you, watching the sunset and then gazing at the stars.
君の頬を流れた涙は ずっと忘れない
The tears that rolled down your cheeks—I will never forget them.
君が最後まで大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I'm sure I'll never forget how you kept waving your hand so big until the very end.
だから こうして 夢の中で ずっと永遠に
So, like this, in my dreams, forever and ever...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
The end of summer with you, dreams for the future, and big hopes—I won't forget them.
10年後の8月 また出会えるのを 信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August, ten years from now.
君が最後まで心から 「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew that you were crying out "thank you" from the bottom of your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, saying goodbye with a smile—it's so painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を...
The greatest memories...
ありがとう！
Thank you! Thanks everyone! See you someday! Bye-bye!
完全生3D Acoustic Live in Summer
[Title: Fully Live 3D Acoustic Live in Summer]